A Guide to the Papers of Charles King, 1827-1914
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Charles King, 1827-1914
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7491
This collection consists of 16 items.
Charles King
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the Library on March 20, 1964.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of 16 letters from Charles King, to various recipients, including J.W. Weidemeyer, D.S. Farrington, Joseph Marshall Stoddart, Miss Storr, Howes Norris, Jr., William H. Rideing, and W. J. Dornuf.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Charles King to J.W. Weidemeyer 1887 August 21, ALS, 1 p.
  Sends sketch of life of his father, Gen. Rufus King. Mentions publication of his story "The Deserter" in Lippincott's Magazine
- C.K. to D.S. Farrington 1890 July 23, ALS, 2 p.
  Sends lists of books and stories he has written.
- C.K. to [Joseph Marshall] Stoddart 1892 February 17, ALS, 1 p.
  Needs money due to the death of his mother and would like an advance on a proposed story.
- C.K. to [J. M.] Stoddart 189[2] February 22, ALS, 1 p.
  Acknowledges receipt of $250 as advance payment on proposed story and states his proposal and agreement for remainder of contract.
- C.K. to [J. M.] Stoddart 1892 June 24, ALS, 2 p.
  Discusses the misunderstanding concerning the current story (serial) for McClure's Magazine and proposed book for Stoddart.
- C. K. to [J. M.] Stoddart 1892 June 30, ALS, 2 p.
  Clarifies his misunderstanding about the proposed stories he is working on, and will write the one for Stoddart as soon as he finishes the serial for McClure. Asks for a $250 advance to send wife and children.
- C. K. to [J.M.] Stoddart 1892 August 9, ALS, 2 p.
  Reports on status of story; will send all chapters by middle of next week and requests money.
- C. K. to Miss Storr 1893 October 15, ALS, 1 p.
  Sends note of regret in reply to Miss Storr's request for a poem.
- C. K. to Howes Norris, Jr. 1894 April, ALS, 1 p.
  Is honored by Norris's invitation to join so illustrious a circle.
- C. K. to "Dear Sir & Brother Delt" 1898 June 25, ALS, 1 p.
  Says there are a number of Greek Letter Society fellows in his California army camp.
- C. K. to William H. Rideing 1901 January 7, ALS, 2 p.
  Discusses subjects for a story requested by Rideing.
- C. K. to W. H. Rideing 1903 January 5, ALS, 1 p.
  Outlines a proposed story about Colonel Webb Hayes for Mr. Rideing.
- C. K. to W. H. Rideing 1905 March 26, ALS, 1 p.
  Comments on an article sent to him by Rideing. Mentions The Youth's Companion. Will send a brief article about Army officer uniforms.
- C. K. to W. J. Dornuf 1907 December 7, ALS, 1 p.
  Comments on the effects of and his use of tobacco and alcohol.
- C. K. to W. H. Rideing 1914 October 3, ALS, 2 p.
  Mentions previous visits to Boston and points of interest. Discusses men he has served with possible topics of interest for a story.
- To Office of Discount and Deposit, Washington 1827 August 21, DS, 1 p.
  Memorandum regarding payment of note to an earlier Charles King (1789-1876).